Hassel Smith papers
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Artwork, 1928-1995, Series 6:; (Box 2; 8 folders)
  - Christmas Cards, 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Doodles, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Fortune Teller, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Sketches, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Artwork by Others (Box 2)
    - Elmer Bischoff, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Robert Wollard, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Relatives [?], circa 1950s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 136)
- Printed Materials, 1928-2003, Series 7:; (Boxes 2-4; 1.25 linear feet)
  Printed materials include clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs about Smith; menus; a poster; and pamphlets and flyers from the California School of Fine Arts, the Mother Lode School run by Smith, and Bristol Polytechnic. There are also miscellaneous printed materials related to Smith's interests in music and politics, including a copy of the pictorial edition of the Communist Manifesto edited by Smith. There are exhibition announcements and catalogs for other artists.
  - Advertisements, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Art Education Materials, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Art Education Materials, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Auction Announcements, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Black Cat Materials, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Bristol Polytechnic, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Broadsides, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Brochures, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Bulletins, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Business Cards, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Calendars, 1966-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - California School of Fine Arts, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cards, 1970s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1928-1932 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Clippings, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Clippings, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 41-42)
  - Clippings, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Clippings, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Clippings, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Clippings, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Clippings, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Commencement Materials, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - The Communist Manifesto in Pictures, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1970s-1987 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1947-1962 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1972-1982 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1994-2000 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Exhibition Announcements: Others, A-E, 1960s-1991 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Exhibition Announcements: Others, F-N, 1968-1983 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Exhibition Announcements: Others, P-W, 1971-1994 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1960s (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1994-1999 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, B-J, 1963-1994 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, K-R, 1953-1989 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, S-W, 1937-1980 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Fitness Materials, 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Flyers, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Gallery Guide, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Stephen Harrington, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - The History of the Audiffred Building, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Information Sheet, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Invitations, 1976-1994 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Lecture Announcements, 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - "Make a Thing," 1953 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Menus, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Mother Lode Art School, circa 1941 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Music, 1960s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Music, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Newsletters, 1977-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notecard, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets, circa 1963-1980s (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Personals, circa 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Political Materials, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Postcards, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Posters, 1972-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1975-1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Programs, 1970s-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Prospectus, 1970s-1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Prospectus, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Prospectus, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: Others, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Robert Wollard, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Robert Wollard, 1970s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - San Francisco Art Institute, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sonoma Open-Air Art School, circa 1953 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - South Africa, 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Tennis, 1970s-1990 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Wedding Announcement, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Photographs, circa 1900, 1941-2001, Series 8:; (Box 4; 0.5 linear feet)
  Photographs are of Smith, his family, his wife Donna, his sons, and stepsons. Found are photographs of Smith's artwork from different periods in his career, of exhibitions installations, receptions, and of Smith's studios. Photographs of others include Robert and Mary Fuller McChesney, Kathryn Swanson, and Elmer Bischoff's wife and son. Also found are photographs of Smith teaching at a Summer Art School in Sonoma County, California in 1955, and at the College of Notre Dame in Belmont, California in 1988. Reproductions of artwork by others include David Park, Henri Lenoir, Cornelius Sampson, and Smith's stepson Mark Harrington.
  - Artwork, 1941-1996, (14 folders) (Box 4, Folder 23-36)
  - Artwork Installation, 1946-1990s, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 37-41)
  - Artwork By Others, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Hassel Smith, 1917-1990s, (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 43-49)
  - Hassel Smith With Others, 1920s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Donna Smith, 1960s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Hassel and Donna Smith, 1960s-1990s, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
  - Smith Family, circa 1900, 1940s-1970s, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 54-56)
  - Mark Harrington, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Stephen Harrington, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Bischoff Family, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Buildings, circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Centre Pomidou, circa 1977 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Children, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Robert and Mary McChesney, 1950s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Music, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Northwestern University, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Receptions, 1988-2001, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 68-70)
  - Studio, 1945-1999, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 71-74)
  - Summer Art School, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Kathryn Swanson, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Teaching, circa 1988 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Negatives (Box 4)
    - Artwork, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Hassel Smith, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Hassel and Donna Smith, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Smith Family, 1920s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Artwork Installation, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Robert and Mary McChesney, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Summer Art School, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Transparencies (Box 4)
    - Artwork, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Slides (Box 4)
    - Hassel Smith, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Student Work, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Audio Recordings, 1965-1980, Series 9:; (Box 4; 6 folders)
  Audio recordings include reel to reel tape of reviews of Smith's artwork by John Fitz Gibbon and nine cassettes of a lecture series organized by Smith at the San Francisco Art Institute.
  - Reviews by John Fitz Gibbon, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - San Francisco Art Institute Lecture Series, 1980, (9 cassettes/5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 89-)
    Audio recordings of lectures by Peter Linenthal, John Corzan, Ricardo Tringali, Sabrina Ott, Peggy Simon, Jeff Richardson, Joshua Gallup, Joe Smith, Rick Camic, and Toshi Oi.